The History of Sound is a drama, romance, music
film directed by Oliver Hermanus.
In 1917, two young music students attending the Boston
Conservatory bond over a mutual love of folk music.
They reconnect a few years later, embarking on a
song-collecting trip in the backwaters of Maine.
Lionel, played by Paul Mescal.
David, played by Josh O'Connor.
Lionel's Mother, played by Molly Price.
Samantha, played by Alison Bartlett.
Bob, played by Michael Schantz.
Older Lionel, played by Chris Cooper.
The History of Sound is a 2025 period romance drama film directed by Oliver Hermanus, written by Ben
Shattuck, and based on a pair of his short stories: "The History of Sound" and "Origin Stories".
It follows the relationship between two men, Lionel (Paul Mescal) and David (Josh O'Connor), who meet in 1917 while attending the New England
Conservatory of Music, and after World War I travel together recording folk songs of their countrymen in rural Maine in the winter of 1920.
The film had its world premiere at the 2025 Cannes Film Festival on
May 21, where it was nominated for the Palme d'Or.
It was released in the United States by Mubi on September 12.
The film explores themes of world war i, boston,
massachusetts, conservatory, folk music, road trip.
The tone is emotional.